Dr. Khalifa: أعوذ بِٱللَّهِ مِنَ ٱلشَّيْطَـٰنِ ٱلرَّجِيمِ
Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem
The Test Begins.
[7:12] God said to Satan, "What prevented you from prostrating when I ordered you?" He said, "I am better than he; You created me from fire, and created him from mud."
So, this verse obviously is after the rebellion, and after deciding to give the human being
a body, this body that's made from the earth's material, and giving Satan a body made from energy,
or made from fire, literally.
If you go many, many years before that, Satan thought he can be a god beside God, and this
created the different opinions among God's creatures in God's kingdom, where the vast
majority upheld God's absolute authority, and the tiny minority agreed with Satan to different degrees.
And after that, God decided to call Satan's bluff, and make him, give him a dominion and constituents.
Those who agreed with him will, are to become his constituents, and the planet Earth is to become his dominion.
And the, the plan called for, in fact, this was after putting all those creatures to death.
And then, this verse here has to do with telling the angels that they will serve the human beings
on this earth. They drive the wind, guarantee the provisions, guard them, serve them,
because they serve us. Angels serve us, even though we are the rebels, and they are the ones who
upheld God's absolute authority, but they are participating in the plan that God is carrying out.
And this is exactly why we were talking about this last night, where they beat up the disbelievers at the end.
Because they served them with the hope that they will come back to God's kingdom.
They will redeem themselves. They will repent. They'll apologize for the mistake they, they committed.
But then, when the life comes to an end, and the person is a disbeliever, then they beat him up, because
they served him all this life, they provided him with all the means to redeem himself,
but then at the end he died as an unappreciative of God.
So, we understand all this by looking at this verse.
So,
[7:12] ... "What prevented you from prostrating ...
means you, we are not cooperating, we are not participating
in serving the, the human being.
This may indicate also that Satan did not want to guarantee the happiness and welfare of any human being.
He wanted to keep his options open, because he is supposed to act as a god,
meaning, he is supposed to make everybody happy and wealthy and healthy and perfectly alright.
But he didn't want this guarantee.
He wants to be, he wants to be free to punish whomever he wills, persecute whomever he wills, and help
whomever he wills.
So, this is why he did not prostrate before the human being.
When God told him that he will be a temporary god, this meant that he was supposed to take
care of his constituents and make them perfectly happy.
So, maybe he wanted some exit in case he cannot do it.
and say "oh, I'm just persecuting god."
But of course, his failure is glaring now.
Number 13,
[7:13] God said, "Therefore, you must go down, for you are not to be arrogant here. Get out; you are debased."
So, this, this is a confirmation of his dismissal from God's kingdom. Number 14,
[7:14] Satan said, "Grant me a respite, until the Day of Resurrection."
[7:15] God said, "You are granted a respite."
[7:16] He said, "Since You have willed that I go astray,* I will skulk for them on Your straight path.
In this verse 16, Satan acknowledges that everything happens in accordance with God's will.
And it is God's will that we will, that we have a free choice.
God wills that we will.
And that all His creatures will, because this rebellion indicates that God's creatures have freedom of choice.
In fact, the first, the very first verse we read indicates that God's creatures can say "no."
God said "fall prostrate," and Satan said "no, I will not."
So, it indicates, if this did not happen, we will never know that God's creatures have freedom of choice.
So, Satan said, in number 16 here,
[7:16] ... "Since You have willed that I go astray,* I will skulk for them on Your straight path.
[7:17] "I will come to them from their front, from their back, from their right, and from their left, and You will find that most of them are unappreciative."
Okay, 17, 7:17, remember this verse, because you will see it.
We, we experienced it, and we see it all around us, that Satan comes to the human being from
his front, back, right, and left, and never runs out of tricks to divert us.
This place right here is his number one target.
Because people come here, and what, what do they come here for?
They come here to worship God alone, uphold the word of God alone.
This is exactly what Satan does not want.
And he will put up all kinds of obstacles, and all kinds of tests, persecutions, in many, many different and strange ways.
It is good, because this guarantees that all God's people are solid believers.
They're unshakable, no matter what happens, or who says what.
[7:17] "I will come to them from their front, and from their back, and from their right, and from their left, and You will find that most of them are unappreciative."
I think one of Satan's objectives is to show God that some humans are worse than he is, than Satan.
And it's true. Some humans out-satan Satan.
Satan is hoping that may, God may have mercy on him when He sees that some creatures are worse than he is.
I recall this fellow, when I was talking in Los Angeles, and this
professor at Chicago Seminary came out and gave a talk that the Quran is hallucinations by Muhammad.
And immediately after him, I gave a talk that the Quran could not be the word of human being. It has to be
God's, the word of God, and here is the physical evidence.
And I gave some details of the miracle, including the total of the numbers in the Quran.
When you take all the numbers mentioned in the Quran and add them up, the total is divisible by 19.
So, these, these people from the Islamic, American Islamic College in Chicago, also the same city,
they stood up and instead of attacking Dr. Hamilton, they attacked Rashad Khalifa. They attacked me.
The guy who said "the Quran is hallucinations by Muhammad" is okay.
But the person who stood up to say "the Quran is the word of God," they attacked me and they said
"you didn't count the Shadda (geminate), Arrahman. There is a Shadda on the RA. You must count two RAs.
"Muhammad (محمد) is, is five letters."
Well, he had written before that, that Muhammad is five letters.
And I think his objective was because in the appendix 2 or I had published that if you
add Ibrahim, Muhammad, and Rashad, the values of this and that, so they want to mess this up.
And he wants Muhammad (محمد) to be written Muhamamad (محممد). You know, two Ms.
So, when he stood up and mentioned his name, I said "oh, you're the fellow who thinks Muhammad should be five letters."
And even the Americans laughed, who are not Arabic speaking people.
He said "yes, if you put five coins on top of each other and you look at them, how many do you see?"
Dr. Khalifa: I said "it depends on the angle."
A man: (unintelligible) was very quiet, just (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
A man: By the way, the sequence of talk was just, I mean, Dr. Hamilton was, was talking before Dr. Khalifa and nobody knew,
I mean, everyone was gonna talk about. He went and talked about
Quranic hallucinations of Muhammad, exactly before Rashad talked, and then Rashad talked
A man: immediately after him. I mean, who, who, who put that order?
Dr. Khalifa: Who planned it this way?
A man: And how many people were talking, that was three-day seminar or something.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: It was three days and they put people at random. You know, this,
A man: they didn't organize it. It was not the chairman who organized it, they didn't even know who he was.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, they thought the, they thought the chairman of the session was me.
A man: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: They were about to kill him, you know.
Dr. Khalifa: Atif was there and Ihsan was there.
A man: Yes.
Atif: All (unintelligible), all his games and just he was expecting everybody to be angry and mad and he gets Rashad.
Atif: And he throws his last coin and said "oh, aren't you the one who's saying you are messenger?"
And he got up while everybody's sitting there, then he goes and said "repeat."
Atif: "You gotta give me one", you know. And he said "yes." He did it. And you know, I think the guy was just, you know,
Ihsan: (unintelligible) A man: Not getting what he did.
Atif: "Oh, he was the one who's saying he's a messenger of God."
Atif: (unintelligible) You know, I was just listening, and I'm sure the guy was shocked.
Atif: He was expecting a revolution, a coup, and all that. Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Ihsan: (unintelligible) I remember
Atif: I think he finished all his arguments and no, no response from the audience, he said
Atif: "oh, you're the one who's saying you are messenger."
Dr. Khalifa: You're right.
Atif: (unintelligible) to that. He was trying to get his
Atif: point (unintelligible) Ihsan: finish (unintelligible)
Ihsan: But then he run away, you remember, when he didn't see the thing, (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: He rushed out so fast, Ihsan thought he was going to get a gun or something and she got worried.
Dr. Khalifa: I said "don't worry, Ihsan. I think the angels gave him a diarrhea or something." Because he rushed so fast.
Ihsan: I will never saw him, again.
Dr. Khalifa: He rushed so fast, he had a blind man with him.
Dr. Khalifa: Of course, they're all blind, but this one is, also his eyes are blind, not just his heart. Ihsan: He left the blind one.
Dr. Khalifa: And he was helping this blind man. He left his blind friend and ran,
Ihsan: And (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: and never saw him again.
Atif: But all the (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Rasool.
Atif: Some of the audience were (unintelligible).
But because every time (unintelligible) Rashad, (unintelligible) he did
If you look in the Quran, you count Qaf, for example, two halves are in the Quran (unintelligible).
So, you count them, let's say, 50, 59.
Khalifa counted 57,
You see in this way, you're, let's say you're right. But he's also right.
Atif: Now, that Rashad Khalifa's 57 has a miracle with it. He counts 59, he has no miracle with it.
Ihsan: Yes.
So, if you, if you go really fair, cause they should have,
Atif: if you count it Rashad's way, it's 57. You wanna count it your way, you can count it your way.
Atif: It doesn't come out (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: You have nothing.
Ihsan: There is no Qaf there to count.
Atif: I feel it was so fair, at least one of them hadn't even found it.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Atif: "Please, don't be upset", he counted that he was right, it was 57. And you wanna count it, he counted 59, but it...
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, he said "if you consider there are two methods of counting. One of them is what your eyes see",
which is what Khalifa is suggesting.
Dr. Khalifa: And one is your way. If you wanna count the Shaddas as 2, fine. Go ahead and do it.
Ihsan: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Because some... he looked Pakistani or Afghani or something, Ihsan: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: one of the professors. Ihsan: I think he was,
Ihsan: I think he was Iranian.
Dr. Khalifa: Could be. Ihsan: His accent was Iranian, he looked Iranian.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, Anyways, so he said,
it was like having two boxes, one is full of jewels, one is full of garbage. Open the one you like.
Dr. Khalifa: You open this box, there's lots of jewels. You open this one, there's a lot of garbage in here.
Ihsan: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: They, they (unintelligible)
Ihsan: (89:14) إِنَّ رَبَّكَ لَبِٱلْمِرْصَادِ
Dr. Khalifa: So, this fellow is worse than Satan. He would out-Satan Satan. That's for sure.
I mean, what are we trying to say?
Dr. Khalifa: We're trying to say "the Quran is from God, and here is physical evidence."
Dr. Khalifa: What is he trying to do?
Ihsan: I don't know.
Dr. Khalifa: He'd like to destroy it.
Dr. Khalifa: Now, I mentioned the numbers specifically, because it has nothing to do with spelling.
Ihsan: Yeah. (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, no, Edip's discovery of the Al-Fãtehah has nothing to do with spelling or writing. It was nothing.
Because sometimes they say "oh, the Quran is oral."
Well, it's right there, written.
One of their big things, I'm sure you heard that, they say "the Quran is oral."
Dr. Khalifa: Have you heard that argument?
A man: Yeah, (unintelligible) "It was memorized, transmitted..."
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, transmitted orally.
A man: Orally, and then later on...
Dr. Khalifa: Right, so I, so I asked him "what was the first word they were revealed in the Quran?"
(96:1) ٱقْرَأْ
Dr. Khalifa: [96:1] Read, ... A man: [96:1] Read, ...
Dr. Khalifa: What is it, read lips?
Dr. Khalifa: Even now, if they read lips, it's 19 times when you read Al-Fãtehah.
Ihsan: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: So, God is, God is killing all the excuses.
Atif: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: The first revelation... excuse me.
Atif: It could be all of us. (unintelligible) count (unintelligible)
Atif: But (unintelligible) to count them right.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Atif: But Edip's, Edip's discovery is blown out.
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Atif: And I think it was probably because he was tampering because he was describing some (unintelligible)
Atif: one day, (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: The first revelation spoke about IQRA' (ٱقْرَأْ) and the pen.
Atif: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: (96:4) ٱلَّذِى عَلَّمَ بِٱلْقَلَمِ
He taught by means of the pen.
Dr. Khalifa: So, what do you do with the pen?
Atif: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible).
They have... and the second revelation was entitled "the pen."
The first revelation is "read", and it had "the pen" in it.
And the second revelation was the pen. Obviously, God knew they will say that.
Dr. Khalifa: So, they will do anything to destroy God's miracle.
A man: And they have Hadith that says, "read." "I can't read."
Dr. Khalifa: Right. Yes.
Ihsan: We found it in the Bible, by the way.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Right.
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible) The Bible, the book of Isaiah.
It said "the angel came to the unlearned man" or something, "and told him, read."
He said "I cannot read."
A man: Very strange. Dr. Khalifa: Very strange.
A man: Book of Isaiah?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Keikhusro found it.
Ihsan: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: The Book of Isaiah. Ihsan: Yeah, I have a copy with that.
Dr. Khalifa: This is exactly the story they gave us in Hadith.
Ihsan: Yes.
Ihsan: Exactly. Dr. Khalifa: They probably took it from there.
Dr. Khalifa: There were many things taken from the, from the Bible.
Ihsan: Yes, a book in Hadith (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Like the Hadith about Heaven having, what, an eye never seen, Ihsan: Never seen.
Dr. Khalifa: and the ear never heard, and never imagined by human being. Ihsan: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Word for word, I saw it in the Bible. Ihsan: Yes, (unintelligible)
A woman: Then, God said, okay, go and study, come back."
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Go learn how to read and write, and come back.
[7:18] God said, "Get out therefrom, despised and defeated. Those among them who follow you, I will fill Hell with you all.
[7:19] "As for you, Adam, dwell with your wife in Paradise, and eat therefrom as you please, but do not approach this one tree, lest you transgress."
Now, we know that all descriptions of Paradise or Heaven are allegorical. So,
[7:19] ... do not approach this one tree, ...
is probably a law that God gave to Adam and Eve to uphold.
And the law is symbolized by the tree.
But we learn from this, 19, 7:19, that Heaven exists.
It was created.
Then, when God created the seven universes, and it still exists today, and the righteous go straight to it. They do not die.
[7:20] The devil whispered to them, ...
Satan started to work on them.
[7:20] ... in order to reveal their bodies, which were invisible to them. He said, "Your Lord did not forbid you from this tree, except to prevent you from becoming angels, and from attaining eternal existence."
So, one of the tricks of Satan is lying. He's a liar. This is a lie.
And this is why those who are fighting us are lying right and left.
It's God's law that they argue against the truth with falsehood.
In other words, they're following their teacher, Satan.
This is, this is good.
If you look at page 467, verse 5 says,
[40:5] Disbelieving before them were the people of Noah, and many parties after them. Every community attacked their messenger to neutralize him. And they argued with falsehood, to defeat the truth. Consequently, I punished them; how terrible was My retribution!
So, they're just following the steps of their master, Satan.
[7:20] The devil whispered to them, in order to reveal their bodies, which were invisible to them. He said, "Your Lord did not forbid you from this tree, except to prevent you from becoming angels, and from attaining eternal existence."
So, what is the story of their bodies? Where were their bodies?
They were down here on earth.
They were up in Heaven, and their bodies were here on earth.
And this is something that, that happened to me personally, I'm passing on this information to all of us.
But apparently it happens often.
It happened when the, when the prophet Muhammad was taken to receive the Quran,
He was taken to a different place, which is even farther than Paradise, but he also visited Paradise.
We see this in Sura 53:17, 18.
17, where he saw the tree that Adam and Eve ate from.
It happened to Ihsan.
This definitely happened to you when you were fired from your work.
Dr. Khalifa: Do you know the story of Ihsan?
A woman: No.
Dr. Khalifa: You don't? She was working, she was talking to Aunt Margaret in Sweden on the telephone.
And all of a sudden, people came in, they saw her incoherent.
So, they took her to the hospital. They called her children.
Both of them are doctors, and of course, they're thinking in terms of this world, what was it, a stroke? Is it a heart attack? Is it what?
But she was like she's not here.
She was walking. She walked with them, went to the hospital.
Meanwhile, she... what did you see? You,
you saw a gathering of a lot of people, and, and a tall, tall huge figure that she understood to be Abraham.
And this is interesting because the only, the only prophet who was identified to me was Abraham, also.
And that, when she came to, she was in the hospital, and she, now take it from there. What did you see?
Dr. Khalifa: What happened? Ihsan: I think it's a confirmation for us because
Ihsan: so, because then when I told him that, then he told me about it.
They were taking me out. Then, there was all the prophets and (unintelligible).
Ihsan: And Behrouz also saw the same big figure, big, big... Dr. Khalifa: But that's....
Dr. Khalifa: We always have confirmation, Alhamdu Lillah.
This coming Friday, Behrouz will give the Khutbah, and he will, he will tell us about confirmation of how the revelation comes.
That's another issue.
Dr. Khalifa: But when you came, in the hospital, you opened your eyes and you were in the hospital.
Dr. Khalifa: Then, what was the first, your first question was what? Ihsan: My eyes (unintelligible)
Ihsan: (unintelligible) never told, I was talking to them. I,
I talked to my daughter, called her on the phone. I was in the, she
Ihsan: she told me that I told her...
Dr. Khalifa: No, you didn't call her on the phone. You gave the phone number to somebody and they called her. Ihsan: Yeah,
Ihsan: Yeah, but they thought, I, I will to put me on the phone. I'll talk about that.
They put the (unintelligible) to write anything, sign anything.
They have no idea what I wasn't in there at all.
My body was there. And I was talking, but at the same time I was somewhere else like,
my soul was somewhere else.
And I saw a gathering of all, it seems like they are all prophets and messengers, I think.
I could see their faces. They were taking someone that was huge,
was very tall, and very proportionate, like the statue of liberty, or maybe more.
And they were all (unintelligible) five (unintelligible), which was almost the same, clothes, and (unintelligible), or (unintelligible).
(unintelligible).
Ihsan: Everyone, I mean, always, and he was back, but (unintelligible) because I knew that he was talking to them. Subhan Allah.
Dr. Khalifa: But they were not prophets, Ihsan. You said they were just people, millions of them.
Ihsan: Yeah. In fact, a lot of people, but he was the one speaking. I think, I think now that maybe they are.
Dr. Khalifa: No, there aren't, there aren't that many messengers.
Ihsan: But they were like the (unintelligible). Then, the guy came, and he was talking to (unintelligible).
And he was talking to them.
And I was, and to me at the same time, because I was talking to (unintelligible)
Ihsan: I didn't see my parents, but I was... yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: What was the first question when you came to in the hospital from people?
Dr. Khalifa: I just wanna say what, how the bodies on earth feel like.
Ihsan: (unintelligible)
Ihsan: My daughter "you killed us" "you're killing me."
Dr. Khalifa: "You scared us to death."
Ihsan: (unintelligible)
Ihsan: They were all crying. I have (unintelligible)
"I, I don't know. Why, why am I...? What is this? Who, who's sick?"
Ihsan: He said "there's one in hospital, there"
Dr. Khalifa: "Why am I in the hospital?"
Ihsan: Yeah, I mean, I don't know what it was because
there were two things happening at the same time,
Ihsan: something with me and something on the, on the earth.
Dr. Khalifa: Ok, so, you were talking to Anne Margaret on the telephone.
Ihsan: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: Next thing you know, you're in the hospital.
Dr. Khalifa: So, you told them "what is going on? Why am I in the hospital? What's happening?" What did they say?
Ihsan: They, they say that I was, that,
that they were called and they talked to them, they said. And they put me in, in the car, took me to the hospital.
I mean "hey, what's happened? what's, what's happened? (unintelligible)"
I said, I told something to my son and as he put it, I was not quite awake yet.
Ihsan: Because I was, I was (unintelligible), because I was, I had no clue, I (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Did you get scared?
Ihsan: Yeah.
Ihsan: I, I didn't know what was going on. I had to call everybody and tell them "I'm not, what did I tell you the last thing?"
She said "I have to go. I have to go."
"I have to go enjoy", but I had already Prayed.
(unintelligible)
I said "I, I didn't have to (unintelligible).
We were talking to three people.
Ihsan: She said "you were crying, crying, crying, crying and you said 'I have to go, I have to go.'"
Dr. Khalifa: Ok. There was some example of having,
Dr. Khalifa: confirmation of having the body here and the soul somewhere else, wherever that is.
A man: So, when the,
A man: when the God asked this Satan to prostrate, He's basically saying and prostrate with just the body, not the soul (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Dr. Khalifa: This is the idea of prostrating to the human being.
A man: With the body, the soul (Unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: Well, the plan was clear to everybody and so, because from this,
Dr. Khalifa: the information that God gave us, everybody knew what the plan was.
A man: What, what was the plan? I mean...
Dr. Khalifa: That, that the, all the rebels are put to death and will be brought to this world and the angels will serve them
Dr. Khalifa: and guard them
Dr. Khalifa: and then after the test is over, everybody will be either redeemed to God's kingdom or sent to Hell. A man: How did we (unintelligible)
A man: And if it was the plan, Satan was also part of the plan and then
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: as he says, God willed him to be like this, so he's not, he is really innocent.
Dr. Khalifa: He is what?
A man: He's really innocent. God willed that...
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, he's trying to blame it on God.
But God gave him the freedom to choose.
Because everything ultimately is in, in accordance with God's will.
In other words, he's telling God "You could have made me obedient."
God doesn't want robots.
And it's not up to Satan to decide that.
And we know the law that God does not inflict an atom's weight of injustice.
So, as God is revealing more and more of His information and we're understanding the total picture
more and more, but what in 20,
[7:20] The devil whispered to them, in order to reveal their bodies, ...
because their bodies were down on earth and he wanted them to get out,
get evicted from Heaven and go down to their bodies which actually happened.
The minute they broke God's law, they were sucked into their bodies down here on earth.
Also at the beginning of the plan, since Adam and Eve didn't do anything wrong under the new circumstances,
they deserved to be in Heaven until they committed disobedience.
In other words, they listened to Satan. Therefore, they belonged in his kingdom which was prepared down on earth.
As long as they listened to God, they were in Heaven.
Dr. Khalifa: The minute they listened to Satan and ate from the tree, they, they went down to Satan's kingdom.
A man: But also,
Atif: Their bodies (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Atif: Their body covered (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: That's a good point.
A man: Rashad, (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: That's a good point.
Let's see,
[7:21] He swore to them, "I am giving you good advice."
which is a lie.
[7:22] He thus duped them with lies. As soon as they tasted the tree, their bodies became visible to them, and they tried to cover themselves with the leaves of Paradise. ...
A man: (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: No, of course, there were gardens here on earth as well, but we have to,
we have to look at this
(7:22) وَرَقِ ٱلْجَنَّةِ
Dr. Khalifa: the expression in Arabic is Al-Janna (ٱلْجَنَّةِ) which is the same expression where they were.
A man: (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, maybe their bodies were up there in Heaven not down on earth.
Ihsan: But also, Janna (جَنَّةِ) was mentioned for garden.
Dr. Khalifa: No, but see, the word that's the same word that is used.
A man: There is (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Al-Janna (ٱلْجَنَّةِ)
Dr. Khalifa: The Jannah, the Paradise.
Dr. Khalifa: Also,... Hmm? Ihsan: (unintelligible)
Ihsan: They were there (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Go down therefrom.
Ihsan: Ok.
Dr. Khalifa: Just that the way I have it in the, the movie script that I wrote that God sent the angels to bring a couple hundred pounds of
of mud from the planet earth and took it up there. And who was asking about falling prostrate before the body, Mehri?
Dr. Khalifa: So, this had to be up there.
A man: Yes, the body must be up there because after this, God says, go down on the earth.
Dr. Khalifa: This, Ihsan just said in Arabic, yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: So,...
A man: (unintelligible) it could be covered (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: But no, actually, (unintelligible) translation.
A woman: If the prostration happened in the Heaven, then they can go down.
Dr. Khalifa: Then, we shouldn't put physical limitations on the body going up there or coming down here. If God wants to
move the bodies from the earth to Heaven, He'll do that.
So, we have to just keep this, reconsider this, the position of the bodies whether they are down here on earth or up there in Heaven.
Dr. Khalifa: But this is a good point, Atif, they cover, covering their bodies with the leaves of Paradise.
A man: Would the Arabic word for body have a different meaning or is it very specific?
Dr. Khalifa: No, it's very specific here. This word used in a few places like when Adam's sons,
one killed the other one, they said, bury the body.
Dr. Khalifa: It's the same word.
A man: They mistranslated this one.
Dr. Khalifa: Saw'ati (سَوْءَٰتی)
Dr. Khalifa: Hmm?
Edip: Other Tafsirs (unintelligible) mistranslated, other Tafsirs.
Dr. Khalifa: What did they say?
Edip: (unintelligible) that
Edip: They said but you see here (unintelligible).
A man: (unintelligible)
Edip: Cover.
Atif: Cover. (unintelligible)
Edip: Yes. (unintelligible)
Atif: (unintelligible)
Edip: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Oh.
Atif: (unintelligible).
Ihsan: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Okay, in 24 it says,
[7:24] ... "Go down as enemies of one another. ...
It says,
[7:24] ... "Go down ...
So,
obviously this is after the, after they saw their bodies.
So, this is shaping up as having the bodies up there.
Dr. Khalifa: Then, maybe my movie script is, is correct.
Atif: (unintelligible). Dr. Khalifa: Mã Shã Allãh.
Atif: Yeah. (unintelligible)
Atif: Well, (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: No. Eskun (اِسْكُنْ)
Dr. Khalifa: Eskunan (اِسْكُنْنِ). The word is Taskun (تَسْكُنُ), dwell, live there.
Atif: (unintelligible) soul (unintelligible) for the body (unintelligible)
Atif: (unintelligible) soul. Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Atif: When the body...
Dr. Khalifa: No, but the body is, was invisible to them.
Their bodies were invisible meaning they were in a different dimension.
It's like we don't see the angels or the jinns now who are right here with us.
Dr. Khalifa: But they are in different dimension.
Atif: (unintelligible) when God created Adam, created him from, from dust (unintelligible)
When He (unintelligible) Adam, you know, you know, Well, Subhan Allah (unintelligible)
Atif: your mind (unintelligible) it's the body. So, when He told angels, I'm creating...
Dr. Khalifa: A human from clay.
Atif: (unintelligible) He, He makes (unintelligible) the body from the mud (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. Now I'm, looking at this that they cover themselves with leaves of Paradise is very significant and then followed by
[7:24] ... "Go down as enemies ...
So,
[7:24] ... "Go down ...
Dr. Khalifa: after seeing their bodies means their bodies were up there.
A woman: Isn't that like when we go to the space, we don't feel our weight but we have the weight?
Dr. Khalifa: No, but see the body has to be protected somehow. Of course, God will do that.
A woman: I mean they had, they had the body but they didn't know that. I mean, they, they couldn't...
Dr. Khalifa: They couldn't see them. Yes. A woman: see that.
Dr. Khalifa: Their bodies were invisible to them. This is... A woman: Yeah.
Feroz: Also, when, when you were taken up, something you saw the other prophets, you know, their bodies.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, they looked like the way they looked here on earth.
Edip: Rashad, the Arabic expression
لِيُبْدِىَ لَهُمَا مَا وُۥرِىَ عَنْهُمَا مِن سَوْءَٰتِهِمَا (7:20)
Edip (Speaking Arabic): (unintelligible)
Edip: Their body was. Maybe, the, part of their bodies, that's why they saw their bodies.
Dr. Khalifa: No, that's because....
Edip: ‌Because there's a reason (unintelligible).
Atif: (unintelligible) (7:20) لِيُبْدِىَ لَهُمَا مَا وُۥرِىَ عَنْهُمَا
Atif: Some parts was, they were aware of how the, some parts they were aware of (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, what you're thinking, yes. No, it... Atif: (unintelligible)
Atif: (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: No, because when you go back let's see...
(7:22) بَدَتْ لَهُمَا سَوْءَٰتُهُمَا
It didn't say: بَدَتْ لَهُمَا مَا وُۥرِىَ سَوْءَٰتُهُمَا
Ma'uria (مَا وُۥرِىَ) means the body was invisible. The whole body was invisible.
Because if you look, if you look at, what's the verse number here?
Dr. Khalifa: 27, 22 excuse me,
A man: What is the (unintelligible)?
Dr. Khalifa: 22 says,
[7:22] ... their bodies became visible to them, ...
(7:22) بَدَتْ لَهُمَا سَوْءَٰتُهُمَا
Edip: Oh, yes. The thing, it means...
Dr. Khalifa: But Ma'uria (مَا وُۥرِىَ), Ma'uria (مَا وُۥرِىَ) does not imply, does not imply a part of the body. Edip: It means part.
Edip: It means from (unintelligible). Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Dr. Khalifa: So, their bodies, their whole bodies were invisible to them. They were in a different dimension
and we're talking about souls.
Until they ate from the tree or until they broke God's law, then their bodies became visible to them.
Dr. Khalifa: They moved to another dimension. In this dimension, they can see us, we cannot see them.
A man: Who's them?
Dr. Khalifa: Angels, jinns, God.
Dr. Khalifa: It's in another dimension. But it's interesting that they could not see their bodies.
Atif: (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: Their bodies were far from them.
Atif: I just wanna (unintelligible) for the body (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: Ecstasy.
Atif: Yeah, in ecstasy. (unintelligible) just like
Dr. Khalifa: You know, we are in this, in this dimension, if we have out-of-body experience, we'll see the body.
Atif: (unintelligible)
A woman: Is it actually invisible or just unaware, could it be unaware?
Dr. Khalifa: No, hidden from you. The word is hidden.
A man: Some interpretations, they say they're eating the apple (unintelligible). Allegorical.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, they knew that Satan lied to them. That's for sure.
A man: Yes, once (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: I, I would, I would leave the location of the bodies hanging until God...
Maybe, maybe, God will want us to know exactly where their bodies were, but
Dr. Khalifa: it seems like they were up there, but maybe in a different location up there.
A woman: If it wasn't there, we wouldn't have the "invisible." When it says "invisible", it should be there.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. A woman: It's like I have,
A woman: I have a hat. When I wear my hat, I'm invisible.
A woman: When I'm invisible, it doesn't mean I'm not here. I am here, but I am invisible.
Dr. Khalifa: Well, it could be anywhere, but the fact that they cover themselves leaves of Paradise
and after that God is telling them, in 24,
[7:24] ... "Go down ...
Dr. Khalifa: This means it happened, it all happened upstairs. Alhamdu Lillah.
Atif: One, one more question.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Atif: that we, we're created from mud (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: and water. Atif: you know, we're, we're
Atif: (unintelligible) we have, when Satan (unintelligible) Adam (unintelligible) a soul (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: "Because You created him from mud." like I said that God's plan was already known.
So, God said, I will give him bodies made of clay. I'll give you bodies made of fire.
Dr. Khalifa: So, they knew that difference. Atif: (unintelligible).
Atif: (unintelligible) soul (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, before, before that, we were all creatures of God and I'm sure we were of different ranks
Dr. Khalifa: or jobs, put it this way, responsibilities, were different degrees of...
Atif: (unintelligible) create means (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Atif: (unintelligible) Adam (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: God created the heavens and the earth. The whole earth was new, it was, came from nothing and so did the human bodies.
Even the souls were created.
(39:62) ٱللَّهُ خَـٰلِقُ كُلِّ شَىْءٍۢ
[39:62] GOD is the Creator of all things, ...
Atif: (unintelligible). creating Adam (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Say it again. Say the question again.
A man: The souls were there, souls of Adam and Eve were there (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, yeah. Definitely. Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: Because God gathered all, all of us and had us witness Him as our Lord and Master.
Atif: (unintelligible) soul (unintelligible) body (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: God assigns, let's think of a human being being born right now. God takes one of the souls
that have been put to death and assigns it to that body.
So, the process is happening now. It happened then except to Adam and Eve had to be, Adam had to be created initially.
And then after that is the human reproduction
and every baby that is born gets a soul assigned to him or her. Obviously, God wanted this story to
the details to be revealed over a long period of time. Every, every piece of it is timed.
Dr. Khalifa: And usually God puts the details in such a way that it will give to every generation a satisfactory explanation.
Cecilia: (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: [7:27] O children of Adam, do not let the devil entice you as he did when he evicted your parents from Paradise. He removed their garments to expose their bodies. He and his tribe see you, while you do not see them. We appoint the devils as companions for those who do not believe.
Dr. Khalifa: What do you understand, Cecilia, from this?
Cecilia: (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. Well, the garment of righteousness, remember?
Cecilia: And so the garment of righteousness (unintelligible).
Cecilia: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: To become exposed.
Dr. Khalifa: Well, let's read... yeah, go ahead.
A man: I was reading in the book a few years ago and this reminds me in that book,
it was going to explain how our physical body in this three dimensional world is actually very
bad quality or the lowly part of all qualities when we were saying, when we, we are attached with this
three dimensional world, start a person in the ocean that he wants to swim and (unintelligible) and have some oxygen,
I mean like a person that is like a big (unintelligible).
Now, we're saying that we were in Paradise and we were like a soul.
And as soon as we disobey God's law and we eat that, from that tree, right there, as a punishment of that work
A man: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. That's a good simulation. A man: Their body was
A man: exposed, our body, as if it was something that made trouble for us and as a punishment appeared with us and
A man: we became a, a physical being instead of a, a soul.
Dr. Khalifa: Well, I think let's, just for the, it will be, I think, sufficient for us. This,
maybe, this is what God wants us to know at this time is that they were out of their bodies.
Their bodies weren't visible to them. They were in Heaven. Everything was perfect.
The minute they broke God's law, they were back into their bodies. Then, their bodies became visible just like as we are now.
But before this happens, until they broke God's law, they were free, they were in Heaven. Because the body is not anything really, so...
like when the righteous go to Heaven, what happens?
They leave their bodies and they go to Heaven. And Heaven is fantastic. They're having a lot of fun.
So, this is the way Adam and Eve were. When they broke God's law, they were trapped into their bodies.
And then, their bodies became visible to them. Now, what we were not sure about was where, where exactly were their bodies
Dr. Khalifa: that were not visible to them. I didn't pay attention to that.
Edip: Rashad, this Paradise, Heaven may be changed to earth at, at that time because the thing because...
Dr. Khalifa: No, no, no, no, there's no possibility of that because
Dr. Khalifa: people go to Heaven now. So, where do they go?
Edip: There are many Paradises now, but...
Dr. Khalifa: No, it's Al-Jannah.
Edip: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: It was one Jannah that Adam and Eve went to.
Atif: Jannah.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: There's no Jannah on earth. I can tell you that.
Edip: There's one another question that always I wonder, but
what the answer for this is. What is the existence of Adam? The existence of Adam starts from the creation of
being from mud (unintelligible) clay or before that (unintelligible)?
God doesn't mention the first creation, the first existence before Adam.
Edip: Because our first understanding is that...
Dr. Khalifa: ...43 in this same Sura
[7:172] ... They all said, "Yes. We bear witness." Thus, you cannot say on the Day of Resurrection, "We were not aware of this."
When did this happen?
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, Edip. When, when did this happen? 172.
Edip: (unintelligible) the creation of Adam.
Dr. Khalifa: No, it couldn't be.
See, when, at the creation of the body of Adam,
the, the clay body of Adam, all the humans were dead. They were already put to death as we see in Sura 67.
Ok. We have, we have to put the pieces together now. Let's look at 67, page 562 verse 2.
[67:2] The One who created death and life for the purpose of distinguishing those among you who would do better.*
So, God created death. Now, the way I see it now, understand it now, is
when, when we rebelled against God, God put us all to death, the first death, remember?
Two deaths for the unrighteous, one death for the righteous.
We were all put to death with the stipulation that we'll be brought into this life at the specified time
and given the chance to redeem ourselves.
So, when you go back here to 172, God says He summoned all the human race before Him.
Obviously, they were not dead yet.
And He, He told them
[7:172] ... "Am I not your Lord?" ...
And we all bore witness that He is our Lord.
Dr. Khalifa: So, these are some of the things that happened before the creation of Adam's body.
Edip: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: And Adam was included in this 172. He was just one of the human beings.
So, after this was done, and the natural instinct of worshipping God alone was put in us, we were all put to death,
and then the plan, the execution of the plan started.
God created the body of Adam from clay, told the angels, fall prostrate before this body. You're gonna serve.
And then, God assigned one of the humans, who happens to be Adam, to this body.
Then, Eve was assigned to the clone. God cloned a body from Adam's body,
Dr. Khalifa: and assigned the second human being, Eve, to that body, and then told them, you, you know the rest of the story.
Edip: There's a word that's confused, Rashad. There's word "creation." "Creation", I don't know.
Dr. Khalifa: No, I said "create the body."
Edip: Right. Yes.
Edip: But when (unintelligible) translate in Turkish, "creation" means just from nothing,
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Edip: just create.
Edip: This creation of Adam starts from this.
Dr. Khalifa: No, remember the body, create the body of Adam.
Dr. Khalifa: But before the creation of the body of Adam, Adam existed.
Edip: I think it's, it's translated a form in Adam, because KHALAQA...
Dr. Khalifa: No, the creation of body, the creation of Adam's body, yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Creation of Adam's body, I'm, I'm very careful with this, because before the creation of Adam's body, Adam existed.
Edip: I think the...
Dr. Khalifa: If you wanna go back to the very beginning, God created Adam, and you and me, and
every other creature, initially.
Dr. Khalifa: And we were all wonderful in God's kingdom until, until the Great Feud happened.
Edip: That, now, I found an answer to this question.
Dr. Khalifa: Let's have it.
Edip: That
Edip: Adam didn't exist before the, the expression would be, would be in this way,
Edip: God created the creature, and then named him Adam.
Dr. Khalifa: Right, there you go. Edip: Then, He wanted to create the, yes.
Dr. Khalifa: There you go.
Edip: I think this is it. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: So, when we put all these pieces together, it is obvious that God created all the creatures.
They were all in His kingdom. Everything was going nicely, until the Feud happened.
The Feud happened when Satan had these ideas, and then the creatures had different opinions,
the vast majority upholding God's absolute authority, a small minority agreeing with Satan.
And then, this small minority was given another chance to submit.
The animals and the stars and the trees submitted, but the humans continued to, to defy God and agree with Satan.
And then, the creation of the, the execution of the plan, which is, we're all familiar with now.
I think the location of the bodies, obviously is not relevant, where the bodies were.
The point is they were invisible to them until they broke God's law. Then, they were sucked into their bodies
Dr. Khalifa: and sent down here to Earth to start the test.
A man: Can I ask something?
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
A woman: (unintelligible).
The second goal is the idea that (unintelligible) that the souls are hurled into the body, that each body,
A woman: each soul has its identified body,
A woman: and it's put into it because of what it has done. Dr. Khalifa: Right. Yes.
A woman: (Unintelligible)
And their Lord called down to them, you know, and, and said that, that they had,
that they had not followed what, what He said,
[7:22] ... "Did I not enjoin you from that tree, and warn you that the devil is your most ardent enemy?"
That was just to let us understand that each body,
A woman: that the bodies, souls are assigned to their bodies, specific bodies, and have (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: What is the first thing we do when we come to this world?
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Dr. Khalifa: The soul is assigned to the body, and the first thing we do "oh, no!"
And on top of that you get a spank.
Dr. Khalifa: Everywhere, everywhere they cry.
Atif: I think that's what she's saying, I think (unintelligible) just threw me out of the body, and there (unintelligible).
Atif: So, that's why she doesn't see, at the minute, she (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: It doesn't matter. Yes.
Atif: (unintelligible). Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Atif: And she was aware (unintelligible). Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Atif: I think (unintelligible). Dr. Khalifa: What happens? Yes.
Atif: I just, I was having fun (unintelligible) and once (unintelligible) sucked back in body, I'd be Dr. Khalifa: Exactly
Atif: I don't know (unintelligible). I have nothing (unintelligible), nothing important.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. This is why I asked you, what was the first thing you asked when you, when you came back?
Dr. Khalifa: "What is happening? Why am I here? Why are you here? What are you doing here? What happened?"
Ihsan: I couldn't have done anything with my body.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Ihsan: She said that, the, the police stopped her because she didn't know how to put the lights on in the car
Ihsan: and, and help her to go to the hospital, and I had no idea. I was sitting in the back of the car and I had no idea what was going on.
Dr. Khalifa: Did they tell her, why don't you turn the lights on?
Ihsan: Yes, the police told her (unintelligible). Dr. Khalifa: Did she say? Oh.
Atif: (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. Atif: (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: Wait a minute. Slow down. Slow down. Because this is wonderful, also. I forget that Atif has all these experiences.
He's telling about somebody who had an out-of-body experience.
Dr. Khalifa: And they were operating on the person?
Atif: They were having some dental work on his teeth.
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, dental work. Ok. Go ahead.
Atif: Because he didn't know. (unintelligible)
All the work on his teeth is when he got out of his body.
His mother was sitting out in the waiting room.
And as soon as he got out, you know what, doctor and nurse was "the guy doesn't move, doesn't talk, doesn't do nothing."
So, they called for (unintelligible), you know, "a state of emergency for my life."
Atif: And they got the team and they started pumping his chest and giving him, you know, regular fluids and
Dr. Khalifa: And he was watching. Atif: That's right.
Atif: And they were rolling around having fun watching him (unintelligible)
And these kids (unintelligible) about to die.
You just think the fact that usually people don't die in the dental office.
(unintelligible)
But the, you see, the doctor was so nervous, so scared, (unintelligible) everybody,
he went outside (unintelligible) in the waiting room
And his mother was sitting there.
And he lifted the bottle in his hand, giving him fluids, trying to get him back. And he went there still.
I went there. And then, I went by my mother.
I (unintelligible) her left shoulder.
I'm looking. That's not the way you say it. (unintelligible).
I looked in the (unintelligible) magazine.
Actually, I wanted to see what she was reading.
And then after a while, I decided to go back.
So, I went back.
(unintelligible)
I went back to his body. So, he revived.
So, the doctor and nurse got him back. They never even got him back. He was just outside.
And after he finished, he went to his mother,
and thought, and of course, after they got him back, the doctor went to his mother and said "oh, we're so sorry your son
"was in different room. He, we almost lost, lost him. But we worked hard and got him back.
"And we're so sorry for what happened."
And that, you know, before what happened, so after his mother took him back, he told her, you know
"all this stuff happened, I was out of my body, I was just roaming around."
Of course, (unintelligible) "What are you talking about?"
You know, I told her "yeah, I was out. You were sitting in the chair by the window. I was right here by your shoulder."
"And you were looking at the magazine."
She said "yes."
"And you were reading an article about so and so."
She said "yes. How do you know that?"
"Because I was out there. I was looking at you."
So, I said "you know, the time was out."
He didn't even care about what they were doing to his body.
Atif: They stick needles on him. They beat him up. They...
Atif: He was having fun. He was having fun. Dr. Khalifa: Exactly. Yes.
Atif: I was thinking, you know, it could be like you said.
Adam had been outside having so much fun in Paradise, my God.
Atif: He didn't care about small things (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: Besides, he had never seen his body before that.
Atif: Yeah, that's another thing. That was a shock and... Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
A woman: Rashad, if we're going to (unintelligible).
A woman: had no record or impression of the needles, the pain, and whatever.
Dr. Khalifa: There's no pain. A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: There's no pain. A woman: When he goes back in, he has no record of...
Dr. Khalifa: Actually, this tells us exactly what Jesus felt when they crucified him.
A woman: That's what I was thinking. No,... Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Because Jesus was gone. This is, I mean, God is, look how God, how God is teaching us. A woman: (unintelligible) Right.
Dr. Khalifa: Real life experiences. This is a physical scientist, a surgeon, you know.
He's not spiritual.
He's also very spiritual. Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: I don't mean it that way.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: But, I mean, he's a scientist. He's very critical. (unintelligible).
And God is teaching us by...
There's a book, of course, that puts all these stories in one book, about out-of-body experiences. Some of you may have seen the book.
They are mainly people who, doctors are operating on, and they say exactly the same thing.
They watch the doctors operating their bodies, and then they decide to go back.
Of course, that's not death. I mean, this, obviously, this fellow was destined to live beyond that point.
But God is teaching us, telling us exactly what the deal is. And this is what we're reading here.
They, Adam and Eve were out of their bodies. They are having fun in Paradise. When they disobeyed God's law, they came to this body, which tells us
this is how you go to Satan's kingdom. Since you listened to Satan,
you didn't listen to God, you belong in Satan's kingdom. So, "goodbye."
Which we see in 26.
[7:24] He said, "Go down as enemies of one another. On earth shall be your habitation and provision for awhile."
Dr. Khalifa: Which is undergoing the (unintelligible).
A woman: (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: I think, yes, we have, I think, we have very clear picture, with a few little details that God hasn't, didn't let us know yet,
Dr. Khalifa: and are not relevant to our generation anyway.
A man: Can I ask you a question?
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, go ahead. You've been very quiet.
A man: At the time of the Feud, all the human beings, all those, I don't know,
Dr. Khalifa: Rebels.
A man: all the rebels were put to death?
Dr. Khalifa: Not at the time of the Feud. There are certain things that happened after that,
including this bearing witness that God is our Lord and Master, putting a certain instinct in us.
And you notice, and go look carefully again at 172, this same Sura.
It says,
[7:172] Recall that your Lord summoned all the descendants of Adam ...
So, God had only the human race bear witness that He is Lord and Master, but not the jinns.
See, your companion represents Satan's point of view.
Your companion will never tell you to do the Noon Prayer, or to worship God alone.
Your companion will do the exact opposite.
So, but God gave us the natural instinct of knowing that God, knowing about God, knowing that He alone is our Lord and Master.
The jinns were the half of the creatures who were closest to Satan's point of view.
Dr. Khalifa: And they're being assigned to us.
Mahmood Abib: When was the time that Satan was exposed?
Dr. Khalifa: You mean as a rebel?
Mahmood Abib: As a rebel.
Dr. Khalifa: This is in 38:69.
Dr. Khalifa: This is the very beginning. This triggered the whole thing. 38:69 is in page 457.
It says,
[38:69] "I did not possess any knowledge about the feud in the High Society.
And you notice after this, again, we're told the story of Satan, eating from the tree.
So, you can see the connection. Do you see the connection? Let's read it. Starting at 67.
[38:67] Say, "Here is awesome news.
[38:68] "That you are totally oblivious to.
[38:69] "I did not possess any knowledge about the feud in the High Society.
Which is called
(38:67) نَبَؤٌا۟ عَظِيمٌ in Arabic.
(38:67) قُلْ هُوَ نَبَؤٌا۟ عَظِيمٌ
It's, it's an awesome, it's a crucial incident in the history of, of the universe.
[38:69] "I did not possess any knowledge about the feud in the High Society.
[38:70] "I am inspired that my sole mission is to deliver the warnings to you."
[38:71] Your Lord said to the angels, "I am creating a human being from clay.
[38:72] "Once I perfect him, and blow into him from My spirit, you shall fall prostrate before him."
[38:73] The angels fell prostrate, all of them,
[38:74] only Satan refused; he was too arrogant, unappreciative.
[38:75] God said, "O Satan, what prevented you from prostrating before the one I created with My hands? Were you too arrogant? Have you rebelled?"
[38:76] He said, "I am better than he; ...
So, this is what, the same thing we read, except we see it connected with the Great Feud.
So, it's, and you see the Great Feud ahead of this,
So, it's the Great Feud that triggered this whole business.
Now before the Great Feud, what was happening?
Adam and Eve and you and I were in existence,
with the angels and the jinns and everybody.
And there was no Feud. Everything was wonderful.
Then, the Feud happened with the rebellion.
(38:69) ٱلْمَلَإِ ٱلْأَعْلَىٰٓ إِذْ يَخْتَصِمُونَ
The High Society feuded.
You can pick up in Farsi some of this.
(38:69) ٱلْمَلَإِ ٱلْأَعْلَىٰٓ
is the High Society.
(38:69) إِذْ يَخْتَصِمُونَ
Do you have KHISAM?
So, Alhamdu Lillah.
This is what triggered the whole thing, is this rebellion.
So, what does God do with the rebels?
The angels suggested, put them in Hell.
The angels said, put them all in Hell.
God said,
[2:30] ... "I know what you do not know."
Dr. Khalifa: I'm gonna give them another chance.
Mahmood Abib: (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: See, the plan calls for putting all of them to death, bringing them in this earth,
having no recollection at all of what happened in the past.
Dr. Khalifa: In other words, the fresh start. It's a whole new, a whole new
A woman: chance.
Dr. Khalifa: chance.
And we are given God's message and Satan's message.
We're making a choice.
As you see, the vast majority of humans are still sticking to their old rebellion.
Why, why are the people hostile to this?
They're not even indifferent. They're hostile to this.
You should talk to some of the people that call us on the telephone.
I mean, why?
Dr. Khalifa: They curse me and my mother. Why? I mean, they never saw my mother.
A woman: They never saw you.
Dr. Khalifa: They never saw me.
And I tell them "what did I do to you?" I mean, and Ihsan, I put her on the telephone. I put her through this the last time.
And she said "we are saying La Elaha Ella Allah. Why, why are you so upset?"
And she said "don't you have any neighbors who are saying 'Jesus is God or son of God'? Why don't you go bother them? Why are you bothering us?"
We are saying "La Elaha Ella Allah. So, it's just fine. Go say what you want and we say what we want. Why are you so upset?"
Dr. Khalifa: What else did he say? I forget.
Ihsan: He said just, he said "Muhammad Rasulullah."
Dr. Khalifa: Oh yes, that was wonderful. Yeah.
Ihsan: (unintelligible).
Ihsan: He said... I said "when was the last time you said Saleh Rasulullah?"
He said "no. Is that mean if I don't said Saleh Rasulullah, that I don't acknowledge Saleh?"
I said "exactly. If we don't say Muhammad Rasulullah, that we don't acknowledge Muhammad?"
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, that was a very good point. She told him
"when was the last time", you said, "God said, don't make distinction among the messengers."
"When was the last time you said La Elaha Ella Allah, Saleh Rasulullah?"
He said "just because I don't say Saleh Rasulullah, does not mean I don't recognize Saleh as Rasulullah."
She said "exactly. Just because we don't say Muhammad Rasulullah, does not mean we don't acknowledge Muhammad as Rasulullah."
Dr. Khalifa: She got him. Parivash: I had,
Parivash: I had, I had a dream
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Parivash: 2-3 weeks ago, and I, in the dream, I was teaching, I was to Iran,
and teach some Mulla (religious scholar), very famous Mulla there.
And I, in, in my dream, I was teaching him something that in my...
God wants to teach me something because in...
when I wake up, I say "oh, I, I have never idea of this."
And I ask him "ok, when you say 'Ash hadu an Muhammadan Rasulullah' ok, tell me what does it mean, the Shahada?"
And he told me "ok, everything that you see."
And I say "ok, we say Shahada, every time that we use the Shahada, even in the court or something, you have to see something...I was"
Parivash: And the Sura 7:172,
Parivash: we saw the God. Dr. Khalifa: We witnessed God.
Parivash: That's why we can say, Ash-hadu Alla Elaha Ella Allah.
Parivash: But have you ever seen Muhammad with your eyes? Dr. Khalifa: Did you see Muhammad? Mã Shã Allãh.
Dr. Khalifa: Mã Shã Allãh. It's fantastic.
Cause "Ash-hadu" is witnessing.
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible).
Parivash: And when I was telling somebody, and he said "no, because you can say of the Quran, is this Shahada enough?
"Because Quran is the shahada." I said "no."
It's just imagine, if you go to the court, and you have to see something and say, yes, I saw it.
But if you have the evidence, still you cannot say "I am witness that this happened."
You can say "I have a lot of evidence," but evidence, witness, that is, you cannot say "I am witness."
Dr. Khalifa: Mã Shã Allãh. This is beautiful. This is a breakthrough.
When you say "Ash-hadu Alla Elaha Ella Allah", I bear witness, or I bore witness,
I am an eyewitness to the fact that there is no god except God, and we have it in 7:172 here.
Dr. Khalifa: Because God said, I gathered all the humans, and they all bore witness that I am their Lord and Master.
Audience: Mã Shã Allãh.
Dr. Khalifa: Have you bore witness that Muhammad is Rasulullah?
Dr. Khalifa: Mã Shã Allãh. In a dream, mind you. A man: (unintelligible)
A man: When in that Sura that I'm thinking that's why God called them liars.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Yes, exactly.
A woman: God called them liars.
Dr. Khalifa: It says,
(63:1) نَشْهَدُ إِنَّكَ لَرَسُولُ ٱللَّهِ
Dr. Khalifa: We bear witness that you are God's Messenger, because they...
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, this is...
Parivash: Yeah, even you, after I, I, I tell someone in a dream, I said "no, still you can say, because of the evidence."
Parivash: Okay, you can say that we have evidence that he is A man: Yes.
Parivash: It is a, the (unintelligible) but not you. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: There is a very short (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Because we were eyewitnesses that God is La Elaha Ella Allah, He is the only God.
Dr. Khalifa: But we were never eyewitnesses to the fact that Muhammad is Rasulullah.
A man: Now that they say this, they are lying.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, exactly.
Dr. Khalifa: Because they did not bear witness that Muhammad is Rasulullah. Did you, did you catch this?
Edip: I know. In addition, I'm thinking on this.
Edip: Just accept the...
Edip: (unintelligible).
Edip: How can a person be eyewitness that he is messenger from the evidence? Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Edip: No, no, how? Dr. Khalifa: Right. I was gonna say that.
Edip: No, no, I am criticizing the subject, and during the time of prophet Muhammad when he is live also,
Edip: how can it be possible to see that he is messenger?
Dr. Khalifa: Exactly.
Edip: You don't see that he received
Edip: the WAHY and Dr. Khalifa: Revelation.
Edip: also from clues.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: This is what I'm saying that even at the time of the prophet Muhammad, this is what Azar brought up.
Even at the time of the prophet Muhammad, they, they cannot witness the fact that he is Rasulullah.
Just he's saying he's Rasulullah.
And then, you think about it, examine the evidence, whatever, and make a decision.
Dr. Khalifa: But they don't witness the revelation coming down,
Edip: Yes, (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: or Gabriel coming down during... This is, this is nothing to witness.
Therefore, the only thing is Shahada, is La Elaha Ella Allah.
(unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: You're sitting there quiet, you've been here almost 24 hours, you didn't tell us about this.
Edip: But in another verse, Rashad....
A woman: yesterday that something came up and yeah...
Edip: Waiting for what, 22, the last verse of 22 says,
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
وَجَـٰهِدُوا۟ فِى ٱللَّهِ حَقَّ جِهَادِهِۦ ۚ هُوَ ٱجْتَبَىٰكُمْ وَمَا جَعَلَ عَلَيْكُمْ فِى ٱلدِّينِ مِنْ حَرَجٍۢ ۚ مِّلَّةَ أَبِيكُمْ إِبْرَٰهِيمَ ۚ هُوَ سَمَّىٰكُمُ (22:78) ٱلْمُسْلِمِينَ مِن قَبْلُ
(22:78) لِيَكُونَ ٱلرَّسُولُ شَهِيدًا عَلَيْكُمْ وَتَكُونُوا۟ شُهَدَآءَ عَلَى ٱلنَّاسِ
Edip: About what?
Dr. Khalifa: About the man I talked to in Canada, for example, I bear witness that he was a disbeliever.
I bear witness that I gave him the message and he did not agree with it.
You will bear witness that you talked to the guy who a PhD student
for three hours telling him "God alone, Quran alone," and he wouldn't listen to you.
This is what
(22:78) وَتَكُونُوا۟ شُهَدَآءَ عَلَى ٱلنَّاسِ
You will bear witness.
We will be called to bear witness on those people.
Dr. Khalifa: That we gave them the message of God alone and they refused it.
Edip: Shahidan (شَهِيدًا) that means that at the same time to exit, maybe.
Edip: Shahidan (شَهِيدًا)
Dr. Khalifa: Bear witness. When I bear... Let's talk in quote. Edip: Cuase only...
You say "yes, I gave him a hundred dollars."
Alright, so this person gave this person a hundred dollars.
Bearing witness.
Obviously, there will be disputes on the Day of Judgment. And the Quran says, they will deny
idol worship, even though they were idolaters.
Dr. Khalifa: So, there'll be witnesses.
A woman: (unintelligible). Dr. Khalifa: Yes, yes.
Dr. Khalifa: So, Edip: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Everything will be very clear.
Atif: Also, (6:24) كَيْفَ كَذَبُوا۟ عَلَىٰٓ أَنفُسِهِمْ ۚ
Dr. Khalifa: Yes,
(6:24) كَذَبُوا۟ عَلَىٰٓ أَنفُسِهِمْ
They lied to themselves.
Dr. Khalifa: Wonderful, wonderful. I think we'll stop right here and just continue discussions and questions.
Atif: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: These are very heavy verses.
Atif: That's what's Eve creation. Was it really mentioned that Eve was created from Adam?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. (4:1) خَلَقَ مِنْهَا زَوْجَهَا I remember that.
Atif: But this means Eve was created from Adam.
Dr. Khalifa: Cloning with feminine features.
Atif: But nothing mentioned, at least from creating.
Dr. Khalifa: Also, God says.
(31:28) مَّا خَلْقُكُمْ وَلَا بَعْثُكُمْ إِلَّا كَنَفْسٍۢ وَٰحِدَةٍ
Your creation, your resurrection is like one person.
Dr. Khalifa: Adam is the master plate. You know, in printing, they make a master plate. They make copies from it.
A man: Eve's own body was created from mud (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: Exactly. Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: But Eve, Eve and... Eve was through cloning.
Atif: (unintelligible). Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: I mean, cloning now is theoretically possible.
In fact, they do have cloning from other creatures.
I, I did some cloning myself, by the way, of carrots, of carrots, carrots. I published it in Nature.
I forget that I was a scientist some day.
Nature magazine is a very respected magazine, and they don't publish anything unless they go through a lot of quality screening.
I have cloned some carrots.
tissue culture system. So,
pictures are published there. I mean, I have some copies.
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible) is not the only scientist around.
Ihsan: In this way, (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: No, no, that's another one. That's, that's a hormone, a growth hormone.
Ihsan: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: They put it in a gel block on one side, cause this side to grow faster than this side, so it curves.
Dr. Khalifa: All of them curve. The one that was not treated continues to be straight.
Atif: Let me ask you (unintelligible). You know what,
(unintelligible) You pick somebody's heart. The guy is dead, but his heart is still alive.
Atif: What kind of life is that? I mean,...
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: The body is still
Atif: a live thing.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Are you talking about the soul?
Atif: The soul is gone. Freshman's dead with a car accident. You pick his heart, his kidney, his eyes and everything.
And he has to be alive also. The difference between a dead heart and a live heart.
Atif: So what's, what's actually... what's life? I think about this a lot.
Atif: What's the life? What's the life in there? Dr. Khalifa: Ok. I think what...
Dr. Khalifa: Ok. I think what you're talking about, the, the entities of the human person, the components of the human person.
And they always eliminate this part.
But if you wanna really be more specific, the human is a body, a spirit, and a soul.
So, a body is this, but it's without life.
The spirit makes the heart pump and the lungs breathe.
Dr. Khalifa: The soul is the person.
Atif: Ok, I just, I just wanna focus here.
I just remember the guy who was telling you the story about his body.
So, he was already out of his body, but his body is still alive. But his soul was free. I mean, he played with it. He could have (unintelligible)
Atif: He squeezed it and everything. It was filled...
Dr. Khalifa: The spirit is part of the physical being.
Atif: Ok, so, his organ was living, but he was really, soul was out. So, it's just,
Atif: You're right so it has to be (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Atif: There's no, there's no, there's no activity in the body then
Atif: a body with activity in it, and then a body was a tree.
Dr. Khalifa: Exactly. Look at Jesus. Let's look at what happened to Jesus. Jesus, the person, left.
And he left the spirit and the body.
They put the body, and the spirit is part of the physical being.
They put the body on the, and then the body bleeds, and then, mechanically, there's no blood to pump.
Dr. Khalifa: So, the spirit leaves. And the body is being left.
A man: So, the spirit leaves the body.
Dr. Khalifa: The soul. Right. A man: The soul.
Atif: Soul. A man: The soul.
Dr. Khalifa: Soul. The person leaves.
A man: Yes, the soul leaves. Atif: The soul first.
Dr. Khalifa: Then, the spirit is, is,
Dr. Khalifa: You have two entities, the spirit and the body.
A man: Yes. And then, the body dies.
Dr. Khalifa: Then, the spirit leaves. The body dies.
A man: The spirit is a separate entity or?
Dr. Khalifa: The spirit is... You can think of it as the word of God that goes... A man: The mechanics.
Atif: This is the thing. Well, you can think of it as a symbol of somebody's dying. Just somebody dies (unintelligible)
alive for 20 years.
Atif: (Unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: They keep the, the heart alive.
A man: But why separate the, the spirit and the body?
Dr. Khalifa: They are two components of the physical being.
But they're two separate components.
A man: But when God says that I blew into him from My spirit, then what does that mean?
Dr. Khalifa: That's the spirit that caused life.
A man: That causes our body to function. Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Atif: But maybe we could now think of anything as a (unintelligible) growing because (unintelligible) piece of skin. (unintelligible).
Growing from your own cells.
Atif: (unintelligible) put back in your body.
Atif: (unintelligible). Something like that. Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible)
Atif: (unintelligible)
A man: So, spirit is just like the body but it has...
A man: I mean, like the soul, obviously, you know, the...
Dr. Khalifa: It's the person.
A man: It's the person and the right and wrong and all that.
Atif: If it's the right, it is actually the (unintelligible) is our thinking one (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Oh yeah, the intellect is in the soul.
Atif: Yeah, because the body... the heart of somebody who's, who's (unintelligible) is already dead but it's still functioning,
Dr. Khalifa: There's no intellect in it.
Atif: There's no nothing in it. It's just...
A man: Once I noticed that all of us, I mean, all nations, different languages, without realizing, we admit that
A man: when I say "I", I'm not my body.
A man: Because if you notice, you say "my hand, my face, my head." Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Yes.
A man: My whole body is, for instance, hurting.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: And also, if we realize, also what happens if one of my hands gets, actually, they cut it, (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: You're still there. Yes.
Atif: It's still you.
A man: So, actually, when we say "my, and my body, my this, my that", actually, we are admitting that... Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: that I'm separate.
A man: The person is that. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: I... Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: The hand that belongs to me, right. A man: But that person... me.
Atif: Now that I remember, you got a good point.
Atif: You see, I remember a few been in accidents and being paralyzed from the knee down.
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible)
Atif: And their whole body is sitting there giving sores and troubles. And the guy is saying
"I know everything." You know, you go to college, you graduate, have PhDs., and...
Dr. Khalifa: She was talking about (unintelligible).
Atif: That's right. (unintelligible).
Atif: A year ago, there was a guy from some kind of university in Europe was completely paralyzed. He was a genius in mathematics.
Atif: And he's also (unintelligible) against God. He's just completely this way.
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible)
Atif: And he's sitting there.
Atif: (unintelligible) the name.
Atif: Cause the guy, he talked through special aids. And he's paraplegic and moved nothing.
And he's there, you know. And he's so angry because his whole body is down here. And I think he realized, that's not him, I mean,
(unintelligible)
Atif: You can be up to here, but still you have your soul.
Audience: (unintelligible). Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Mahmood Abib: Is that Stephen Hawking?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, Hawking. Do you know (unintelligible) yesterday?
Mahmood Abib: For Hawking?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, and the computer talks for him. That's amazing.
Atif: Exactly. (unintelligible) And he goes all over the world talking about his experience at talks.
Atif: He goes all the way...
Dr. Khalifa: Yesterday, what he said was "if the rate of expansion of the universe was one millionth
"of the speed faster, we will have nothing.
"It would be just space now.
"And if it was one millionth of the speed slower, we will be compact" or something "and life cannot exist."
"We will not be here."
Dr. Khalifa: He said "the rate of expansion of the universe is precise, is so precise."
Atif: But he doesn't know God. Dr. Khalifa: But he doesn't recognize God.
Atif: He doesn't know God.
A woman: And he's sitting there. And he's, he just has... Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: He's just really
Atif: A soul hanging on his head. Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: He really is a genius.
A man: (unintelligible)
Atif: It's funny. Yeah, it's funny he mentions his soul, he's just speaking to this blue piece of (unintelligible). And everything is lost.
And I think it, I think it shows how much blessing we get because, you know, he's a guy with his
Atif: biggest brain maybe in the whole world, now. And he's absolutely prevented from, from living there. He just...
A man: Just recently, in San Francisco, some, some person died. Just one person died.
A man: He donated six different organs to six different people.
Atif: Yes.
A man: (unintelligible) Who do you think it is?
A man: (unintelligible) for a life (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Sure.
A man: His wife (unintelligible) has donated (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: I wouldn't do it mainly because of maybe (unintelligible), because of the humiliation the body goes through.
Dr. Khalifa: Because I've seen it. A man: Also, but
A man: what's the difference if you're dead and gone? What do,
Dr. Khalifa: It doesn't make any difference. I want my body cremated and flushed down the toilet. A man: why do you care about the body?
Dr. Khalifa: But I don't want it, I don't want it pulled around with it.
Dr. Khalifa: They hang it, they hang them like a cow from a ceiling, and is really mistreated.
Atif: They don't do that.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Yes, they do that. Because that's what they do.
Dr. Khalifa: Listen. Ok. Listen to what, what do they do Mahmood Abib: "Pull him up."
Dr. Khalifa: with the, to a, they want to...
A man: Rashad, (unintelligible).
A man: Before you get into that, there was a scandal in England that over-enthusiastic, you know, doctors would kill a person.
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, my God. Mahmood Abib: Yeah. A man: for
A man: you know, when you said "I would like to (unintelligible)", you're, you are not already dead.
Dr. Khalifa: "Just hurry up." A man: They need a heart somewhere.
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible). A man: And through enthusiasm they'll just finish you off. That's what they do. Mahmood Abib: Business, business.
A man: This happened in England. It was a scandal. Mahmood Abib: Yeah.
Atif: That was rumor. But I was, I was at this
some of the patients in the ICU were very sick, very sick patients.
They had a breathing machine, and everything, medication for his heart, (unintelligible) and everything.
And I felt so bad about it. And we had orders.
(unintelligible)
Well, half of the family told us to donate the organs.
And I feel so bad about it. Some people just don't take it well.
You know, somebody...
If a family member is still alive and you told him "can I take his heart?"
(unintelligible)
Atif: It's just terrible thing. And there's so much burden on me.
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible).
Atif: As I remember this, this guy was so embarrassed, almost that could not even talk. He wanted to talk to, to his wife.
And I told him, you know, "if something happens to him, we need to do this or that." And he was so angry, almost so (unintelligible).
Atif: She (unintelligible) so fast. I, I was so suspicious.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, the fight. Atif: She was hoping to finish him.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Atif: She was just giving information so fast (unintelligible).
And I also remember. I got, I got shocked. My God, this woman wanted to finish him.
Atif: And I was so attached to the patient. I didn't want him to get over this and recover.
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, she hated him.
Atif: Oh, yes. She hated him. She had so much fight, she was gonna get out of here. (unintelligible).
(unintelligible).
Atif: Some people do have this syndrome. "Yeah, finish him. Yeah, and his heart, yeah (unintelligible)."
Dr. Khalifa: "Where do I have to sign?"
Dr. Khalifa: "Can you do it yesterday?"
A woman: "Just take his whole organs."
A woman: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Ok. Yeah.
Atif: Yeah, (unintelligible)
Atif: "You need to take the organs" They have to take everything.
Atif: I mean, just like your surgery, they keep you breathing and everything, they open you and take everything out, everything, but...
A woman: What if he's still alive? I mean,...
Atif: No, no (unintelligible) it could be, I mean, of course, it's very difficult to define the moment of death.
I mean, there have been meetings and meetings, conferences and
(unintelligible) could nobody knows exactly when the moment of death is.
Who, who defines death? Who says this guy is dead or not?
And I think the final thing he decided to do is check the brain.
And (unintelligible) he issues a brain, a brain electricity wave.
And if he lost his wave in the brain location, they declare him dead.
And we always know here that people have been on the breathing machine for years and they just
rise there and they just don't function. Their brain's dead.
And we, we see a lot. So, if the brain is dead, your body is actually dead. Your heart is still beating, your kidneys are still functioning.
And it's amazing when people have brains dead, their body is in excellent shape.
If they ever get to the point where they can transplant brains,
you know, this is the moment when you get somebody back. It just never happened anyway because it's so complicated.
which actually, you know, most probably the brain is the soul, you know.
You get somebody's brain transplant, they actually need to transplant the soul in this body.
It's a perfect body, except the brain is dead.
So, these are the people, young, healthy guys in a, in a car accident. So,
(unintelligible) to their brain.
And these are the guys who have everything clean. You just take the heart, kidneys, everything and give it to somebody else.
Atif: So, the soul is gone.
A man: The soul must be brain.
A man: connected with the brain.
Dr. Khalifa: No, no, no, the brain is just the, it's a physical...
Atif: Yeah, the physical part that expresses the soul.
Atif: It's probably what is that.
Dr. Khalifa: It's the physical tool. It's like you and the computer. You can think of the brain as a computer.
Atif: You're (unintelligible) the computer. Dr. Khalifa: Because you have to run it.
Atif: Yes, if you don't, if you don't have, if you don't know how to run a computer, (unintelligible)
Edip: What stimulates brain to work (unintelligible)? Atif: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: See, the brain is only but electrons moving around, just like the computer exactly.
Dr. Khalifa: Of course, the computer's clumsy. It's a clumsy representation of the brain.
A man: But I've read, I have read articles that just you can add or remove some hormones.
A man: You can do different stimuli. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Atif: (unintelligible) A man: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Because they affect the function of the, of the brain, but the brain is strictly physical.
Atif: Because it stimulate your eyes,
Atif: you know, yes, of course, there's a map of the brain. This is the foot, this is the hand, this is the ear, and mechanically or electrically
you touch these areas and make what you want, which is the physical part.
But for, for, like you're saying, you, you, the real person, you, is the soul.
Cause you're just using these organs for your, for your benefit,
Atif: using the eyes, using the ears, using
Dr. Khalifa: Including the brain.
Dr. Khalifa: I thank God for my out-of-body experience that I had many years ago cause
Dr. Khalifa: I was looking at my body down there and it was just like a piece of rock.
Edip: Cause amount of hormones, who determines that hormone? What determines the amount of the other hormones, that hormone?
Edip: And there must be over all of them that determines the amount of hormones in the brain and their interpretation. Dr. Khalifa: There is.
Dr. Khalifa: There is a maestro. Edip: Yes.
Mahmood Abib: Huh?
Dr. Khalifa: Maestro A man: What happens (unintelligible) a person
Dr. Khalifa: orchestrates the A man: has been (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: levels of the hormones. A man: (unintelligible)
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible) Edip: Definitely.
Edip: (unintelligible) or the physical, it, it destroys the physical by itself or from others but
that soul cannot communicate with our world through this. That's what it says.
Edip: (unintelligible)
A woman: (unintelligible)
Edip: One receiver, radio, we have a receiver or the other station that radiates.
Edip: And one of them this, how do you say it, it doesn't work, how do you say it,
Dr. Khalifa: Nothing happens.
Edip: Nothing happens.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. (unintelligible) transmitter and I receive there. (unintelligible)
A woman: That's when you say the, the brain is dead.
A woman: But here, that's my understanding of what I already know. That's every function we do. That's all that comes from the brain?
Atif: A lot of organs have this own, what we call also mechanisms.
Atif: You know, the heart can keep beating with a special built-in mechanism.
A woman: Does it come from there?
Atif: The, the heart will regulate things, certain things, like the, the, how fast it goes, which, which one to, you know,
which, which way to pump more blood and which to pump less blood.
There's a control, of course, but some organs have their own built-in mechanism.
But the brain has to balance it.
You have to balance the kidney with the heart with the whole balance system.
If you can, one work more than the others, then you lost everything.
So, the brain has that but
you know, you see, like the computer, you have to set exactly for the second, for millionth, millionth of second,
how much blood comes out and how much the heart beats should go and how much blood goes to your
big toe and how much it goes to your feet and
so, all this is exactly controlled.
If you lose the brain, this is what really controlled very much, but,
but the heart, I think, we all have seen it in, in chicken, when you cut them, cut their neck completely
Atif: and let it go, it's gonna run for a little bit.
A woman: Yeah.
Atif: you know, and drains completely. A woman: Yeah, that's,
A woman: Yeah, for a little bit, but if it's for a long time, can they...
Atif: No, no, this, for human beings, it's the same way.
A woman: Oh.
Atif: You know, so, these people, they have to kill machines.
What the machine does is just keep bumping things to the heart and make it come back.
They have to keep putting oxygen down, down the lungs against the will as it go up.
We have to have things work for the kidney.
And also for a period of time.
After a while, everything is deteriorating because your, you can never balance, do the balance as much as the brain.
Atif: Your chemistry is completely screwed up when, when the brain goes away.
Edip: Somewhere they, unless still alive when they make brain surgery on birds and take their brains (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, the lungs are the same way as the heart. It's, it's all mechanical.
Atif: Yeah, the hearts, when we were little kids, we used to get things like the goose lung and blow on it to make fun of it as
the thing that you could see the whole thing like a balloon in and out, do the same thing with that guy.
So, I would be, after he dies,
you just want to (unintelligible) up (unintelligible) and his heart is pumping, you know, the, the blood goes in, oxygen goes back.
And then, they have, you know, we have equipment where we put special pumps inside the heart
and just keep all the blood closed and just pump the blood from the heart.
Atif: All kinds of fancy stuff. And...
A man: What I don't understand is,
for example, if brain does not work properly,
(unintelligible)
A man: bodies malfunction, the spirit malfunctions, or the soul malfunctions?
Dr. Khalifa: Just the body.
A man: Cause
Dr. Khalifa: Body malfunctions.
Atif: And, you know, most probably, (unintelligible), we can procure organs for them.
We do have some functions of the brain that keep things (unintelligible) keep going.
But the part which really does do the thinking and real living, which is the soul,
it's, you know, I'm sure if you open his head, most of them can find a little bruise on it.
This is what qualifies the rest of the brain as OK.
But well actually, we look at it this way, the brain is dead,
which will actually mean that the soul is out.
The brain might have been OK, but we don't know that. I mean, we can't physically say the, the soul is out.
We can't do that. All we can say is that the brain is dead.
Atfi: The brain is dead is actually the soul is out. The brain is intact? Dr. Khalifa: The person is gone.
Atif: Yeah, but I think (unintelligible) the brain is intact. The soul is out. It doesn't work. So,...
A woman: Yes, but I'm here saying that when the brain is dead, the person actually is dead.
Dr. Khalifa: The person is gone. A woman: Yeah.
A woman: Gone.
A woman: But maybe there is some function.
Atif: Oh, yeah, they all function. They are because...
A woman: But the brain is dead, is dead. (unintelligible)
Atif: I think brain....
Dr. Khalifa: Sometimes the brain is not dead and the person is gone. Like case of Bill Schroeder
who lived 19 months without, without the soul.
Dr. Khalifa: The body was functioning. The person was eating and drinking and going to the bathroom and,
Dr. Khalifa: But he didn't recognize... A woman: See, because I knew (unintelligible) I don't know.
A woman: I can't remember the name of this guy, you know (unintelligible)
A woman: He had some surgery. And after, during that, the time of surgery, when surgery finished, he couldn't,
he was asleep in that time.
And then, he couldn't woke up,
wake up and after that, but for a long time, 10 or 15 years, he was, he was in that situation.
A woman: And, yeah, he was dead. Actually, he was dead.
Dr. Khalifa: What happened, what happened after the 10 years?
A woman: And then he, yes, yeah, Atif: Came back.
Dr. Khalifa: Came back? A woman: came, yeah,
Atif: You, you know what this was, it would have been all better. A woman: that's dead.
Atif: Ask, I don't know, ask me, I would have, I have more experience. You just (unintelligible) "did he come back from in 10 years?" I don't know.
Dr. Khalifa: No, this would be like, would be like the people of the cave, you know. They were asleep for 300 years. A woman: No, but the, the man (unintelligible), he was
A woman: (unintelligible) Because of that, everybody knew about him.
Atif: Yeah, I heard, heard about a few days would be this. You know (unintelligible) for 6, 7 years. In one of these days, she came back.
Dr. Khalifa: Perfect. And nothing happened? A woman: Came back?
A man: Does she come back?
Atif: I don't know. You know, I was just reading about it. There's no, I have no experience with her.
(unintelligible) the same way.
But this is why so many families, when they have a loved one, it's just, similar situation,
already brain dead, they always have been pumping for this (unintelligible) with
their loved ones will come back, like these little stories we hear.
And most of the time, it doesn't. And also, your body deteriorates,
sitting in bed, you, you get sore, you get pneumonia, you get all kinds of infections.
And you keep (unintelligible) your body, waiting for it to come back.
And no, and nobody knows if you ever come back.
And you start seeing your loved ones getting in terrible, miserable shape. I mean, you have (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: But, but we have this in the Quran, you know, people of the cave were asleep for 309 years. Atif: Yeah.
Atif: But did anybody walk in the cave?
Dr. Khalifa: They came back and said "let's, let's have lunch."
"Here's some money. Go get us some lunch." They took this ancient money to the market.